The 4K restoration was undertaken by the Friedrich-Wilhelm-Murnau-Stiftung in Wiesbaden from the original camera negative held at the Bundesarchiv-Filmarchiv in Berlin .
The first reel of the camera negative is missing and was reconstituted using alternate sources . Jump cuts and missing frames in 67 shots were
reinserted from multiple prints . An original German release print does not exist . The basis for the colour tinting were two nitrate prints
from Latin America , wich represent the earliest surviving prints of the film , now stored at the Filmmuseum Dusseldorf and the Cineteca di
Bologna . The intertitles were recreated from the flashtitles in the camera negative and a 16mm print from 1935 from the
Deutsche Kinemathek-Museum fur Film und Fernsehen in Berlin . The digital image restoration was carried out by L 'Immagine Ritrovata - - Film Conservation and Restoration in Bologna .
The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari
A Film in Six Acts Written by Carl Mayer and Hans Janowitz
Decla-Film-Gesellschaft Berlin
Directed by Robert Wiene
Art Direction : Hermann Warm Walter Reimann , Walter Rohrig
Cast : Werner Krauss Conrad Veidt , Friedrich Feher
Lil Dagover , Hans Heinz v. Twardowski , Rudolph Lettinger
Photographed by Willy Hameister
The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari
ACT I
There are spirits ... They are all around us ...
They have driven me from hearth and home , from wife and child ...
That is my fiancee ...
What she and I have lived through is stranger still than what you have lived through ...
I will tell you about it
The little town where I was born ...
The annual fair
Him ...
Alan , my friend
Special Edition : Fair In Holstenwall
For The First Time Entertainments of Every Variety
Come on , Franzis , let 's go to the fair !
Don 't go inside , the town clerk is in a vile temper today !
Dr. Caligari
Wait !
I wish to apply for a permit to present my spectacle at the fair ...
What kind of spectacle ?
A somnambulist
Step rrrrright up ! Presenting here for the first time ... Cesare , the Somnambulist !
END OF ACT I
ACT II
That night the first in a series of mysterious crimes took place .
Murder ! The town clerk has been killed . Stabbed in the side with a strange pointed instrument ...
Step rrrrright in ! Presenting here for the first time ... Cesare the Somnambulist !
The miraculous Cesare ... twenty-three years old , he has slept for twenty-three years ... Continuously ...
Right before your eyes Cesare will awaken from his death-like trance ...
The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari
Cesare ! Can you hear me ? Cesare , I am calling you ...
I ... Dr. Caligari ... your master ... Awaken for a moment from your dark night ...
Ladies and gentlemen ! Cesare the Somnambulist will answer all your questions ...
Cesare knows every secret ... Cesare knows the past and sees the future ...
Judge for yourselves ... Don 't hold back ! Ask away ...
How long will I live ?
Till the break of dawn ...
Murder in Holstenwall 1000 Marks Reward
The way home
Alan , we both love her ...
We 'll leave the choice up to her ...
But whomever she chooses , we shall remain friends ...
Night
END OF ACT II
ACT III
Mr. Franzis ... Mr. Franzis ... Mr. Alan is dead ... murdered .
The somnambulist 's prophecy ? !
I won 't rest until I get to the bottom of these dreadful deeds .
I will obtain police authorisation to examine the somnambulist ...
Murder ... Help ... Murder !
Wake him up !
Special Edition : Holstenwall Mystery Solved ! Two-Time Murderer Caught In Third Attempt !
END OF ACT III
ACT IV
Worried because her father has been away so long ...
I had nothing to do with the two murders ... So help me God ...
The old woman ... It 's true ... I tried to kill her ...
by stabbing her in the side with a similar knife to throw suspicion on the mysterious murderer
Is my father ... Dr. Olfen here ?
After the funeral
Night
Cesare ... !
It couldn 't have been Cesare ...
He was asleep at the time ... I 've watched him for hours ...
END OF ACT IV
ACT V
Is the prisoner secure in his cell ?
I must see him ...
Lunatic Asylum
Do you have a patient by the name of Dr. Caligari ?
The director returned earlier today ... perhaps you should speak to him personally ...
He ... himself ... and none other ... is Caligari ...
While the director , now placed under observation , is sleeping in his villa ...
He 's asleep .
Somnambulism
A Collected Edition by the University of Upsala published in 1726
His specialty
The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari
In the year 1783 , a mystic by the name of Caligari
Toured the fairs of numerous villages in northern Italy ,
Accompanied by a somnambulist named Cesare .
For months he sowed panic amongst village folks through a series of foul murders committed under almost identical circumstances
He had entirely subjugated to his will a somnambulist named Cesare ,
Whom he did compel to carry out his nefarious schemes .
A puppet , the exact likeness of Cesare , and which took his place in a cabinet ,
Allowed him to divert any suspicion that might fall on the somnambulist .
My diary
12 March ... Finally ... finally ! a somnambulist has been brought to the asylum for admission
Afternoon ... my desire ... I shall be able to satisfy my life 's unwavering wish !
Now I shall unravel the psychiatric secrets of this Caligari ! now I shall discover if it is true
that a somnambulist can be compelled to perform acts that in a walking state he would never commit and would be repugnant to him
Whether it is true that a sleepwalker can be led to commit even murder ...
An obsession
I must know everything ... I must penetrate his secrets . I must become Caligari ...
You Must Become Caligari
END OF ACT V
ACT VI
We found the sleepwalker out in the fields ...
Mr. Director - unmask yourself . You are Dr. Caligari !
... And from that day on , the madman never again left his cell .
Look ... there 's Cesare ... never allow him to tell your fortune , or you 're dead ...
Jane ... I love you ... won 't you be my wife at last ?
We queens are not free to answer the call of our heart ...
You all think that ... I 'm insane !
It isn 't true ... It 's the director who 's insane !
He is Caligari ... Caligari ... Caligari !
At last I understand his delusion . he thinks I am that mystic , Caligari ! now I know exactly how to cure him ...
THE END
★ ★ ★ THANKS GOD ★ ★ ★ The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari ( 1920 ) ‫Subtitle re-sync edited by Hameedreza Meerforooghy v1.2 - © 2023 Persia